Evening. Hope everybody's doing all
right.
Um
round honestly played out the way we
sort of anticipated. Think there ended
up being
I don't know, like seven tackles, two
guards, couple quarterbacks, five or six
receivers, couple backs, and then and 14
players on defense or whatever it was.
Um so
um
looked at a couple of
uh
And then, you know, I think moving two
spots, it was just more of semantics
than more than positioning more than
anything
else. Um
some interest in the player. So, we felt
like, all right, we'll just move a
couple spots, essentially give up a
fifth-round pick, which is essentially
what the difference is when you actually
do the math.
Um you know, to get a player who I think
you all just spoke with them, but I
would say
I mean, the things that stand out about
him, I mean, toughness, violence,
physicality,
playing style, his intelligence.
I mean, the basic guy wants to step on
your throat in every play. So, which I
would say is sort of embodies what our
football team is about, the way we play,
intense, violent, physical. Like, we're
going to run the football this year.
Um you know, it was an area that we felt
like we wanted to and needed to improve
here in the offseason. Hopefully, we've
done that. And um
I'd say Big Red is hopefully, you know,
a part of that. Like, where is he going
to play? Like, who the hell knows? I
mean, we'll figure out like who the best
five guys are.
And, you know, put the group out there
that we think is going to help us the
most.
Understanding that we'll probably need
eight to 10 guys on the offensive line
here at some point. So, um you know,
he's a player that again, a good
example, transfer up. So, started at
obviously a lower level, and transferred
over to Georgia Tech.
And had a good career there.
Um you know, he was at the Senior Bowl.
Um you know, we spent a little bit of
time with him here um in the spring. I
mean, Cole went down there, worked him
out.
Um so, I mean, he's a player like I
think the whole building collectively
felt strongly about. So, you know,
that sort of worked out the way that we
it hoped it would. So, you know, excited
to get him here, and
we'll be back to the drawing board here
tomorrow. Um I think we got 38, uh
whatever, 59. Kind of like
picking third round just got moved down
there a little bit. So, try to take
advantage of our opportunities here
tomorrow um with those picks. Um I'm
sure we'll get some calls, and you know,
we'll kind of see what makes sense
relative to moving back or sitting and
picking. So, just kind of taking it
here, you know, one pick at a time, but
you know, definitely excited about
Keilan and the things that he brings to
the table.
So, take some questions. I think when
you look at
Did you have a specific moment in
meeting him or or watching him
and that that
Uh yeah, when you put the tape on. I
mean,
everybody that watched him, I mean, your
notes basically say physical, tough,
strong.
Good run blocker, good at the point of
attack. Um he's probably more athletic
than maybe people think he is. Um he's
got some technique things that he can
certainly clean up, which
I think one of the things with the
workout, you know, sometimes you're
trying
the
I mean, how do they apply the coaching?
Uh I mean, I wasn't a player like the
makeup on this guy is like elite.
Like
couple of the metrics that we have in
our and when we grade players, I mean,
in like four or five categories, like
there were one player there's one player
in the draft that our scouts graded the
way that they did, and it was him.
So, like that was like, okay. It We
didn't talk to him at the combine cuz we
didn't need to.
Like and then we might not even
interviewed him at the Senior Bowl cuz
we didn't need to. So, I mean, there was
a couple touchpoints here and there we
felt like, but just put the tape on,
watch the guy play.
And I'd say like the program that Coach
Key runs down there at Georgia Tech, we
got a lot of respect for their program.
I mean, Coach Key is a former offensive
lineman.
Um and again, I think like Big Red, like
who he is, is emblematic in like what
you saw tonight. I mean, the basic guy
was in an Airbnb with him and his wife,
and that was pretty much it. You know,
you see some of these other draft
parties, some of you, you know, you got
it took like a circus. I mean, this
guy's all ball. He's all football,
doesn't really care about anything else.
Wants to punch people in the mouth.
Yep, that works here. So, I mean, that's
what you see on tape, which is I'd say
part of the intrigue with the player.
How valuable is it to you guys that he's
comfortable playing all three positions?
Yeah, we'll see. I mean, he'll probably
play wherever like
he needs to play. So,
I'd say all three inside guys. Like
again, we've talked about this. You got
some guys that are center only, some
guys that are guard only, some guys that
can play all three spots. So, we'll see
how
it goes. I mean,
your ball. So, I mean, where's he going
to play? I mean, we'll see. Like, nobody
knows. So, we'll figure that out as we
go.
Go ahead.
Got through that car accident, had a
pretty pretty bad foot injury. When you
see a player like that that's already
been through something, what does that
tell you about the mental toughness that
you hope for? Yeah, I kind of think it
kind of speaks to his personality,
Aaron. I think that was like the
appealing thing about this player. I
mean, you alluded to the accident that
he went through, but like I said
mentioned a little bit earlier, talked
about a transfer up. I mean, he didn't
start at the biggest program. I mean,
nobody's ever heard of the program that
he started. And then he went to Georgia
Tech, and he made an impact. So, I think
that's speaks to who he is as an
individual, his mindset, and it really
is emblematic of what this program, the
foundation, the principles that that we
talk about, that Demeco talks about,
that I talk about, that the players talk
about, that we want to have in our
players. Cuz in the end,
like you're going to need that on
Sundays. So, I mean, it's He's a really
He's a great kid.
Um cares a lot about football. Um he's
overcome some things. Um you know, I
think his wife is a big influence in his
life. Um I think Coach Key has been a
big influence on him. Um like I said, we
have a lot of respect for Coach Key and
the program that he he runs and and what
he's about. They look, [clears throat]
they won I don't know, nine or 10 games
or whatever it was.
And they probably beat some teams that
they like nobody thought they should
beat, but they have a lot of belief um
in themselves. Um and I think Big Red
certainly falls in that category. With
the offensive line's shortcomings this
last season, uh just what's the timeline
in getting him in
into the lineup?
I mean, the best five guys will play.
So, like whoever those guys are, I mean,
we're not going to put any timelines on
anybody. So, whenever they're ready,
they're ready. And we'll figure out like
who's going to be out there. I mean,
it might start one way, and then it
might shift. I mean, there's a lot of
things that can happen. So, I mean, we
don't put any timelines on anybody. I
mean, the players ultimately determine
what the timeline is. So,
when a player is ready, we'll put him
out there. Um if that's the best option,
then that's the guy that's going to
play.
James Lightfoot, obviously he's an alum
and a football player for Georgia Tech.
Did that help at all with the scouting
process? I mean, you just got all the
schools with uh
Was that helpful at all?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think other than like
them maybe giving more to the alumni
fund, I mean, I probably wouldn't do
much into it. I mean, uh
you know, I mean,
James does a good job. I think the
scouting group does a phenomenal job. I
mean, like the pro staff, the college
staff. I mean, essentially like when we
were going through the draft, we were
looking at each team, okay, what are
their needs, what do we think they're
going to do? And whoever had that team
had an answer in a heartbeat. And
honestly, it played out exactly the way
I thought. So,
I mean, I have a lot of respect and
appreciation for our group. They work
really, really hard. They take a lot of
pride. They care.
They're informed.
And they understand their teams, and
they provide
incredible information so that
ultimately we can make good decisions
for the organization. So, that's the
most important thing.
On his scouting report,
on his scouting report, it talks about
how great of a run blocker he is and how
he's able to maul
the, you know, defensive line in front.
But they say that some of his weaknesses
is pass blocking. How much can Cole
Popovich help him with that? Yeah, I
don't know who said that or like what
scouting reports we're like what reading
or who we're relying on. I mean, all
players have areas that they can improve
and fix. So, I mean,
doesn't matter who they are, what they
are. So, again, I don't know what
scouting report or who said that. I
mean, we don't really care. What we care
about is what they do when they walk in
our program and what what we're going to
ask them to do.
All we want to do is see a player like
take coaching, improve, and apply what
we're teaching. All that's all we care
about. And the same bowl, he took a
couple snaps at center. Were you able to
observe that? What did you think?
Uh yeah. I mean, I think sometimes
probably hard to extrapolate too much,
you know, when a guy just goes down
there in the Senior Bowl for 3 days, and
you know, has a couple snaps, and like
while you're making a projection based
off of that. So,
um again, we'll see how that goes. I
mean, if the guy can put his hand on the
ball, then okay, what does that look
like? And the communication that's
involved with it. So,
again, like when a player walks in the
building, like we'll put things on his
plate, see what they can handle, um and
see how quickly they can adapt and
adjust to what we're asking them to do.
What was I think was was the
the you know, interaction with with this
kid at the Senior Bowl? Was Was this
sort of like the coup de grace on top
from what y'all seen on the tape? Or did
just Was this sort of like put the
period behind this is the way you want
him at on your draft board?
>> Uh yeah, I mean, I think we grade the
player in the fall, and you assign a
grade, and there wasn't a lot of
variation or deviation like after the
season. I think one thing you have to be
careful about is, okay, you spent all
this time in the fall, and then okay,
you start making adjustments or changes
based on like Senior Bowl and all that.
So, I think
our scouts and grades are pretty
consistent throughout.
Um so, you're just evaluating the
player, evaluating the performance. Um
honestly,
I'd be careful to put too much stock in
the senior bowl either way because
again, it's a short
snapshot, small snapshot. So, but
everything is all-encompassing at the
end.
Tape, senior bowl, combine, pro day,
workout,
if you do a visit, those zooms, like
whatever the case may be. So, you try to
accumulate as much information and
create a profile on the player as
possible. And then just try to take that
information and say, "Okay, here's what
we think we have in a player."
Understanding, you know, there might be
some deviation or variation when they
get here. So, it's all part of the
process, all part of the evaluation. To
follow up with Zay's question about Cole
Pop, because obviously he met with Cole
Pop and he went through a little
workout. How much does that interaction
help, I guess, the evaluation process
for you guys? Yeah, it's a part of it.
So, we do that with all of our coaches.
Like we had a number of our coaches out
in the spring. So, whether it's a
private workout, whether they go to the
pro day. I mean, every team has the
ability to basically zoom with the
player three times. So, you have
different touch points. And a lot of
that is like football. So, yeah, we like
we value their opinion. Hey, what do you
think? What information are you
gathering? Is it different than maybe
what we already had or something new?
So, like we value our coaches and their
opinions and what they think of the
player at the various touch points.
Again, it's a snapshot. It's not the
only like we're going making a decision
based off of that. It's an accumulation
over time. Um and I'd say with this
particular player, it's pretty
consistent. What are we getting in
return? Yeah,
yeah, I know you mentioned you'll let,
you know, the position play itself out.
Was the fact that he is multiple, was
that intriguing for you guys or or do
you all envision something more? I'd say
just generally speaking, I mean, any
player if they have some degree of
position flexibility or versatility, I
mean, there's value in that. Again, even
going back to tackle, some tackles are
left tackle only, some are right tackle
only, some can potentially swing and do
both. So, again,
you try to put the player in a position,
just see if if they can handle that
assignment. You might think
theoretically, "Oh yeah, they should be
able to do it." Or he did it here, but
then they come to find out, you like go
down the road, I mean, I'd say just
past experience, I've seen it happen
both ways. Like, "Oh, you think this
guy, he should just be able to project
inside." Or he played left tackle,
should have no business no problem
playing right tackle.
And then you put him over there on the
right side and it's a disaster. It's
like, "Well, let's just keep him over
there where he belongs." So, again, try
to see what a player can handle and
ultimately try to fit him in best where
like they're comfortable, we're
comfortable.
Um and then go from there.
Thank you. All right, thanks.
I'll send you all the schedule for
tomorrow.